<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gnome | Laurent's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/categories/gnome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-01T16:32:01+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Laurent Contzen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #5]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/weekly-report-number-5/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T16:19:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/weekly-report-number-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not much to say in my weekly report this week. I continued my work on the model, went to Geneva for a family meeting (so couldn't work those days) and more of my work was merged into master.</p>

<p>I also dove back into FolksIndividual's code to add the display_name property. Since the last time I worked on it, Jeremy Whiting had made some progress on my first patch. I've now submitted an updated version (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=651672#c21">bug #651672</a>).</p>

<p>I couldn't make it to GUADEC but I saw the (pdf version of the) <a href="http://www.gnome.org/news/2012/07/gnome-outreach-program-yearbook-2012/">GNOME Outreach Program Yearbook 2012</a> and it's great! Thanks to <a href="http://www.dgsiegel.net/">Daniel Siegel</a> and all the people who made this happen!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #4]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/24/weekly-report-number-4/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-24T13:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/24/weekly-report-number-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week my work on the model started to be merged in master!</p>

<p>Before coming back to Brussels I continued moving logic from the view into the model. I then reviewed my patches, submitted them on bugzilla (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=680302">Bug #680302</a>) and those patches were merged into master \o/. I also documented my public API for gtk-doc.</p>

<p>My patch for the bug I mentionned last week about the top contacts group name has been reviewed, corrected and merged.</p>

<p>I'm now going to go on on my work on the model and dive back into FolksIndividual's code to try to complete my patch for the new display_name property.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #3 : My holidays coding station]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/14/weekly-report-number-3-my-holidays-coding-station/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-14T15:11:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/14/weekly-report-number-3-my-holidays-coding-station</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/panorama.jpg"><img src="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/panorama.jpg" title="Panorama around the chalet" alt="Panorama around the chalet"></a></p>

<p>As the title suggests, I'm on holidays in the French Alps. This doesn't mean that my GSoC is on hold, but it means that I'm enjoying a beautifull sight while coding :</p>

<p><a href="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/station.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/station_small.jpg" title="Holidays coding station" alt="Holidays coding station"></a></p>

<p>During this week, I've continued my work on EmpathyRosterModel and EmpathyRosterModelManager. The model now catches all the signals emitted by the manager previously catched by the view. It also now have all the functions needed to be able to completely rely on the model and remove every manager references in the view. As said in my previous post, all of this is pushed on github : <a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy">lcontzen/empathy</a>.</p>

<p>On a side note, I found out that if all your top contacts are offline the group name isn't displayed and the top contacts are lost alone on the top of the roster. I reported it and submitted a patch fixing this behavior (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=679868">bug #679868</a>) (this still needs to be reviewed).</p>

<p>PS : <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1D1cap6yETA">Good news, everyone!</a> I passed my Midterm Evaluation! \o/</p>

<p>Bonus : a better picture of the beautifull sight :
<a href="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/view.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/view_small.jpg" title="&#34;A better picture of the sight &#34;A better picture of the sight&#34;" alt="&#34;A better picture of the sight &#34;A better picture of the sight&#34;"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly report #2]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/08/weekly-report-number-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-08T12:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/08/weekly-report-number-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time flies and it's already time for this second weekly report. Since my last report, I successfully ported empathy-nautilus-sendto plugin to use the RosterView (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678875">bug #678875</a>). I then immerged myself in FolksIndivual's code to try to add a new display_name field (I haven't completed this yet).</p>

<p>I've also begun creating empathy-roster-model, the model designed to be used along with the RosterView. The model will be modular thanks to the use of interfaces. I'm populating the model along with it's first implementation : empathy-roster-model-manager using an EmpathyIndividualManager.</p>

<p>I've created a branch on github where I push my work : <a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy">lcontzen/empathy</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly report #1 : Finally started]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/weekly-report-number-1-finally-started/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T12:16:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/weekly-report-number-1-finally-started</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've finished my exams at my University last week, which means I've finally been able to get started on my GSoC serious business.</p>

<p>After getting on grips with jhbuild and empathy's new parts like the <a href="http://blog.desmottes.be/post/2012/06/15/New-Empathy-contact-list">new roster</a>, I fixed <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678376">bug #678376</a> by making ungroupped contacts being displayed at the bottom of the roster before fixing <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678156">bug #678156</a> by re-implementing the People Nearby group feature.</p>

<p>I'm now working on porting empathy-nautilus-sendto plugin to use a RosterView instead of a EmpathyContactChooser (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678875">bug #678875</a>).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
