<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gsoc | Laurent's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/categories/gsoc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-14T16:36:47+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Laurent Contzen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #3 : My holidays coding station]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/14/weekly-report-number-3-my-holidays-coding-station/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-14T15:11:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/14/weekly-report-number-3-my-holidays-coding-station</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/panorama.jpg"><img src="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/panorama.jpg" title="Panorama around the chalet" alt="Panorama around the chalet"></a></p>

<p>As the title suggests, I'm on holidays in the French Alps. This doesn't mean that my GSoC is on hold, but it means that I'm enjoying a beautifull sight while coding :</p>

<p><a href="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/station.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/station_small.jpg" title="Holidays coding station" alt="Holidays coding station"></a></p>

<p>During this week, I've continued my work on EmpathyRosterModel and EmpathyRosterModelManager. The model now catches all the signals emitted by the manager previously catched by the view. It also now have all the functions needed to be able to completely rely on the model and remove every manager references in the view. As said in my previous post, all of this is pushed on github : <a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy">lcontzen/empathy</a>.</p>

<p>On a side note, I found out that if all your top contacts are offline the group name isn't displayed and the top contacts are lost alone on the top of the roster. I reported it and submitted a patch fixing this behavior (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=679868">bug #679868</a>) (this still needs to be reviewed).</p>

<p>PS : <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1D1cap6yETA">Good news, everyone!</a> I passed my Midterm Evaluation! \o/</p>

<p>Bonus : a better picture of the beautifull sight :
<a href="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/view.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://laurentc.be/pics/blog/view_small.jpg" title="&#34;A better picture of the sight &#34;A better picture of the sight&#34;" alt="&#34;A better picture of the sight &#34;A better picture of the sight&#34;"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly report #2]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/08/weekly-report-number-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-08T12:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/08/weekly-report-number-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time flies and it's already time for this second weekly report. Since my last report, I successfully ported empathy-nautilus-sendto plugin to use the RosterView (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678875">bug #678875</a>). I then immerged myself in FolksIndivual's code to try to add a new display_name field (I haven't completed this yet).</p>

<p>I've also begun creating empathy-roster-model, the model designed to be used along with the RosterView. The model will be modular thanks to the use of interfaces. I'm populating the model along with it's first implementation : empathy-roster-model-manager using an EmpathyIndividualManager.</p>

<p>I've created a branch on github where I push my work : <a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy">lcontzen/empathy</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly report #1 : Finally started]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/weekly-report-number-1-finally-started/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T12:16:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/weekly-report-number-1-finally-started</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've finished my exams at my University last week, which means I've finally been able to get started on my GSoC serious business.</p>

<p>After getting on grips with jhbuild and empathy's new parts like the <a href="http://blog.desmottes.be/post/2012/06/15/New-Empathy-contact-list">new roster</a>, I fixed <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678376">bug #678376</a> by making ungroupped contacts being displayed at the bottom of the roster before fixing <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678156">bug #678156</a> by re-implementing the People Nearby group feature.</p>

<p>I'm now working on porting empathy-nautilus-sendto plugin to use a RosterView instead of a EmpathyContactChooser (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=678875">bug #678875</a>).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, Planet GNOME]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/hello-planet-gnome/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T19:46:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/hello-planet-gnome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, my blog has been added to <a href="http://planet.gnome.org">Planet GNOME</a> for my GSoC. As detailed in <a href="http://blog.laurentc.be/blog/2012/04/24/hello-world/">my first post</a>, I'm a belgian student so I'm currently studying for my finals but I'll start coding as soon as possible.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.laurentc.be/blog/2012/04/25/my-gsoc-proposal/">My project</a> is about the creation of a new library providing models and widgets to display and choose contacts, and my mentor is <a href="http://blog.desmottes.be/">Guillaume Desmottes</a>.</p>

<p>This blog will be the place to follow my progress all along this exciting summer.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My GSoC Proposal]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/my-gsoc-proposal/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-25T14:51:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/my-gsoc-proposal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As mentionned before, I've been accepted to do a Google Summer of Code for <a href="http://www.gnome.org">GNOME</a>. My <a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/proposal/review/google/gsoc2012/lcontzen/1">proposal</a> is about the creation of a new library providing models and widgets to display and choose contacts. For those who don't want to read the complete proposal here are the interesting bits :</p>

<h3>What is the ultimate goal of your proposal?</h3>

<p>The ultimate goal of my proposal is to develop a new C library providing models and Gtk+ widgets to display and choose contacts that could be used by any GNOME application, a feature that Empathy's developers are considering to implement since a long time.  It has been discussed last year during the IM/Social Hackfest and <a href="https://live.gnome.org/Hackfests/IMContacts%20Social2011/Tasks/ContactChooserDesign">some notes are available on the wiki</a>.</p>

<p>The contact chooser would be integrable in a lot of GNOME application or plugins such as Nautilus-sendto, the Shell's contact search engine, Evolution (which could begin to use Folks and allow to send mails to IM contacts), or any GNOME application which could benefit from IM integration using Telepathy tubes for example.
The library will be usable in C, Python and Javascript thanks to the GObject Introspection support.</p>

<h3>What components/modules will the proposed work modify or create?</h3>

<p>A model of the loaded contacts will be developed and widgets will be built on top of it. This will be developed as a new library that other projects will be able to use. This library will probably be named Folks-gtk, but this name might change during the development if we find a cooler one.
The API will mainly provide :<br/>
  -Functionalities to fetch and display all contacts from Folks<br/>
  -An API to define if one or more contacts can be picked<br/>
  -An API to let the user filter out contacts<br/>
  -Helper code for some common filters (like online contacts)</p>

<p>This will, obviously, be related to Empathy, Telepathy and Folks. To validate the library and its API, Empathy's nautilus-sendto plugin will be modified to make use of it. If time permits, I'll also modify Shell's contact search feature to use it as well.</p>

<h3>What benefits does your proposed work have for GNOME and its community?</h3>

<ul>
<li><p><em>IM integration and Telepathy tubes :</em><br/>
This contact chooser I'm proposing to implement here would help improving IM's integration in the whole GNOME desktop experience. Whatever the application is and whatever the developer wants to do involving IM contacts, he won't have to think about the way to choose contacts or struggle implementing it. Of course, it's not only valuable for developers but it's also profitable for the end users since more applications could start offering more social features.<br/>
Even if Telepathy tubes have been implemented several years ago they are only quite rarely used in GNOME. Vinagre/Vino use them for Empathy's desktop sharing, a really popular and innovating feature, but that's about it. There are at least two reasons which could explain this : the first is that tubes are quite difficult to use, and the second is the difficulty to fetch and present the list of contacts (needed in almost any application implementing social features). Telepathy's team is working to fix the first problem (telepathy-glib now has high level tubes API) and my project would fix the second one.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Contacts coherence :</em><br/>
Since GNOME 3.2, gnome-contacts defined a new way to display contacts in GNOME. Empathy's developers are working with the design team to re-design Empathy's contact list to make it more coherent with the rest of the desktop (see <a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=669484">bug #669484</a>). If more applications are going to integrate social features it's important to stay coherent and offer a coherent way to display contacts in the whole GNOME desktop.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
