<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gsoc | Laurent's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/categories/gsoc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T17:44:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Laurent Contzen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final GSoC Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/final-gsoc-report/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T13:03:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/final-gsoc-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wait, august 19th? Where's my summer? I feel like i just started this GSoC!</p>

<p>Alas, it's already coming to an end. Those two month have been amazing. Let's head back and summarize what I've been doing during this time.</p>

<h3>1. The Proposal</h3>

<p>When I felt I was going to pass my exams and thus was going to have an
exams-free summer, I knew I had to seize the opportunity to try to be selected
for a GSoC. I talked about it with <a href="http://blog.desmottes.be/">Guillaume Desmottes</a>
and we got to the idea of my <a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/proposal/review/google/gsoc2012/lcontzen/1">proposal</a>.</p>

<p>I was really happy to be selected and looking forward to the end of my exams
to start working.</p>

<h3>2. The Work's Beginning</h3>

<p>Around mid june it was finally time to get started. As I stated in <a href="http://blog.laurentc.be/blog/2012/06/27/weekly-report-number-1-finally-started/">my first weekly report</a>,
I begun by fixing some bugs to get in touch with Empathy's code base. I then
ported empathy-nautilus-sendto to the RosterView instead of
EmpathyContactChooser.</p>

<p>It's worth noting that Guillaume's work on the RosterView between my proposal
and my work's beginning quite modified the initial planning.</p>

<h3>3. The Model</h3>

<p>The next step of my work was one of the most important : I created
empathy-roster-model and empathy-roster-model-manager and moved all the logic
out of the view to the model. This took longer than what Guillaume and I thought
initially, but it got merged into master around the beginning of august.</p>

<p>During the model's development I created a new test app in which I created 2
views using the same model. This helped me understanding what goal Guillaume
wanted me to achieve here.</p>

<h3>4. The ModelAggregator</h3>

<p>empathy-roster-model-manager worked great for Empathy but it was way too
Empathy specific to be usable elsewhere. Since the ultimate goal of the project
is to create a library that any project could use I created
empathy-roster-model-aggregator, a new implementation of empathy-roster-model
relying on FolksIndividualAggregator.</p>

<h3>5. A New Internal Lib</h3>

<p>Once empathy-roster-model-aggregator was done and working as it should, I moved
the view, the model (along with model-aggregator, but not model-manager) and
various needed tools like EmpathyRosterContact or EmpathyRosterGroup to a new
directory inside Empathy's tree.</p>

<p>This is one step closer to the goal of the external library.</p>

<h3>6. Gtk-doc and GIR</h3>

<p>If we want this library to be widely used along GNOME projects, it had to be
documented. I therefore added gtk-doc to the project and wrote some doc.</p>

<p>Using Gobject-introspection was also one step in the roadmap. I discovered how
gir functions, created EmpathyRoster-0.1.gir and wrote a small example test app
in Python.</p>

<h3>7. The Future</h3>

<p>So, what's left to do?</p>

<ul>
<li>A part of my code has yet to be reviewed, Guillaume being on holidays.</li>
<li>The library should be moved out of Empathy's tree.</li>
<li>The gir annotations should be completed to eliminate warnings.</li>
<li>There's probably more doc to write.</li>
</ul>


<h3>8. The Asides</h3>

<p>In addition to what I've already talked about I also worked on other things. One
of the most tiring ones was idling on a lot of new IRC channels. I also fixed a
few bugs in Empathy and worked on a patch for Folks.</p>

<p>Unlike what I feared, I found myself quite enjoying writing my Weekly Reports.
It was a nice way to have to take time to evaluate the week's productivity.</p>

<h3>9. The Results</h3>

<p>To sum things up, let's say that :</p>

<ul>
<li>My coding skills have dramatically improved</li>
<li>I finally contributed to Open Source Software</li>
<li>I've had the best conceivable summer job. Not once did I start to work
feeling I "had to" (excepted maybe for the doc writing step, let's be honest).</li>
<li>I've acquired more knowledge about the various aspects of software development
(at least regarding GNOME softwares).</li>
<li>I've lost time on really stupid errors.</li>
<li>I'm quite satisfied of my work.</li>
<li>I have more IRC chans to idle on.</li>
<li>I plan to continue coding and contributing.</li>
</ul>


<p>TL;DR: Amazing experience. 10/10, would do again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #7]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/weekly-report-number-7/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T09:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/weekly-report-number-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After finishing my new EmpathyRosterModelAggregator implementation of the EmpathyRosterModel interface (<a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy/tree/aggregator">aggregator branch in my github repo</a>), I moved all the concerned files to a new directory to have them as a new private library ((<a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy/tree/libroster">libroster branch in my github repo</a>)). This is still in Empathy's tree, but it's ready to be transformed as an external lib.</p>

<p>I then started writing documentation with gtk-doc (<a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy/tree/libroster-docs">libroster-docs branch in my github repo</a>). I lost a few days to get it working "thanks" to the fact that I passed --enable-gtk-docs to autogen.sh instead of --enable-gtk-doc. What a wonderful example of a PEBCAK error that can drive you insane.</p>

<p>I'm now going to finish the docs before trying to bind my library to GObject-Introspection. I'm also going to update my page on live.gnome.org and prepare my final GSoC blogpost.</p>

<p>Little spoiler about this blogpost: This GSoC has been an awesome experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #6]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/09/weekly-report-number-6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T16:24:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/09/weekly-report-number-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, I finally finished the work to move the model logic out of EmpathyRosterView (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=680302">bug #680302</a>) and all of this has been merged into master.</p>

<p>I then started to work on a new implementation of the EmpathyRosterModel interface : EmpathyRosterModelAggregator. This is of course pushed as a branch on my github account : <a href="https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy/commits/aggregator">https://github.com/lcontzen/empathy/commits/aggregator</a>.</p>

<p>Quite short post, but quite satisfying pogress.</p>

<p>PS: My mentor <a href="http://blog.desmottes.be/">Guillaume Desmottes</a> gave me my printed copy of the GNOME Outreach Program Yearbook 2012. It's even better than in PDF!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #5]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/weekly-report-number-5/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T16:19:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/weekly-report-number-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not much to say in my weekly report this week. I continued my work on the model, went to Geneva for a family meeting (so couldn't work those days) and more of my work was merged into master.</p>

<p>I also dove back into FolksIndividual's code to add the display_name property. Since the last time I worked on it, Jeremy Whiting had made some progress on my first patch. I've now submitted an updated version (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=651672#c21">bug #651672</a>).</p>

<p>I couldn't make it to GUADEC but I saw the (pdf version of the) <a href="http://www.gnome.org/news/2012/07/gnome-outreach-program-yearbook-2012/">GNOME Outreach Program Yearbook 2012</a> and it's great! Thanks to <a href="http://www.dgsiegel.net/">Daniel Siegel</a> and all the people who made this happen!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Report #4]]></title>
    <link href="http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/24/weekly-report-number-4/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-24T13:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lcontzen.github.com/blog/2012/07/24/weekly-report-number-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week my work on the model started to be merged in master!</p>

<p>Before coming back to Brussels I continued moving logic from the view into the model. I then reviewed my patches, submitted them on bugzilla (<a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=680302">Bug #680302</a>) and those patches were merged into master \o/. I also documented my public API for gtk-doc.</p>

<p>My patch for the bug I mentionned last week about the top contacts group name has been reviewed, corrected and merged.</p>

<p>I'm now going to go on on my work on the model and dive back into FolksIndividual's code to try to complete my patch for the new display_name property.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
